<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Destroy Today</title>
    <link>http://destroytoday.com</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 20:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 2015</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/in-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 19:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/in-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The end of this year really crept up on me. I spent most of it heads-down working, so I didn’t even think of writing a year-in-review post until the last possible day. I wrote one for &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2012-a-year-in-review&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt; and it felt good to look back at past accomplishments, but I feel like 2014 was just a work-in-progress year for me. Because of this, I’m going to focus on the upcoming year instead and list a few things I want to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ship Cushion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt;, I’m surprised. Not because you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; know about it, but more because I feel like it’s all I talk about anymore. Cushion is the freelancer app I’ve been working on day and night for most of the year. 3 months ago, I rolled out a &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com/beta&quot;&gt;paid beta&lt;/a&gt; and I hope to publicly launch in the next month or so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Use spreadsheets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started working on Cushion, I made a point to be transparent, so I started tracking its &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com/expenses&quot;&gt;expenses&lt;/a&gt; in a spreadsheet. I can’t remember the last time I seriously used a spreadsheet, but I instantly rediscovered how powerful they can be. Coincidentally, my frustration with accounting software has reached defcon 1—I’m essentially paying $30/month for stress. I realized I could save that money and build a custom-tailored system using a simple spreadsheet. It’ll require a bit more manual work, but I’m certain I’ll sleep better at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Continue existing routines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming off my &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/sabbatical&quot;&gt;sabbatical&lt;/a&gt; in June, I decided to establish a few routines. The first was to limit client work to 3 days a week. With Cushion bringing in an income of its own now, this routine has been a possibility for the past few months. The second routine was an uphill battle—getting a gym membership and actually going. I discovered that pairing routines increases the likelyhood that they will succeed, so after a long day of client work, I head straight to the gym. I’m proud to say this routine is on its 4th month and staying strong. *&lt;em&gt;rimshot&lt;/em&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;One week between client gigs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year, I had a serious problem with overlapping client jobs, resulting in the need to take 3 months off to fully recover. I’d like to avoid another burnout, so I’m establishing a new rule for myself—one week off between client gigs. This is much easier said than done, considering the delay and drag of projects are outside of my control, but I’m going to give it a shot and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Book a few speaking gigs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a few small talks in 2014 and it was a lot of fun. I’d really like to speak more, but I’m not sure where to start—I have a lot on my mind when it comes to freelancing, bootstrapping, and working solo. Speaking in front of a crowd once scared me to death, but now I enjoy it and feel I can contribute a lot—specifically jokes that bomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Take more photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, I tell myself I’m going to take photos more consistently, but I always fail. It’s the first thing to go when work picks up. I’m keeping this one on the list, though, because I still think it’s important—I’m always thankful when I have photos to match memories. After a year-long break from Instagram, I plan to return tomorrow. Maybe sharing photos will encourage me to shoot more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Read more books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we moved our studio space to within walking distance of our apartment, I was a subway reader. Now, I need to set aside time if I want to read. I hate that I’ve become accustom to reading headlines and collecting browser tabs of articles I’ll never read. To fight this, I’m going to first try getting in bed earlier and reading before sleep. Then, I might turn coffee time into coffee/reading time. I think it’d go a long way in improving how I feel about my consumption habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Play more video games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in my adulthood, I stopped playing and just decided that I would work day and night. All the video games I once played just sat on the shelf and gathered dust—I forgot what it was like to really get into a game. Jen recently convinced me to buy a PS4 (which didn’t take much convincing at all), so we’ve been getting back into it. Every other night, we’ll set aside our work and take turns playing our game. I’m currently on Grand Theft Auto 5, with The Last of Us next in the queue, while Jen continues the Assassin’s Creed series. I can’t wait to see which games come out in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ride my bike&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a Linus bike a few summers ago with the best intentions, but didn’t ride it much beyond a few commutes to the studio. With so much to see in New York, I feel I’m doing a disservice to myself for not riding on a regular basis. After living here for close to 3 years, I honestly haven’t ventured far beyond my own neighborhood. When spring arrives, however, I can’t wait to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Take a trip outside of Brooklyn every 3 months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with seeing more of the city, I need to see more outside the city. Today especially, I realized I rarely take time off. My friend Frank &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anotherny/status/550381159658835971&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; blocking out time in my calendar every 3 months to just get out of the city. Well, I marked my calendar and I’m determined to stick to it—even if it just means a drive upstate. We’ve gone on a few trips last year with our fellow studiomates and now I’m itching to plan a few of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cushion</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/cushion</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/cushion</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cushion-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;cushion-logo&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt; is an app I’ve been working on to provide freelancers with better insight into their day-to-day and bring a calm to the everyday rollercoaster ride of freelancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;cushionapp.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Scout</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/help-scout</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/help-scout</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/helpscout-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;helpscout-logo&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style='text-align: center'&gt;I’m currently working with &lt;a href='http://helpscout.com'&gt;Help Scout&lt;/a&gt; on an interaction prototype for their mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FiftyThree Paper</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/fiftythree-paper</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/fiftythree-paper</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fiftythree-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;fiftythree-logo&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style='text-align: center'&gt;I recently worked with &lt;a href='http://fiftythree.com'&gt;FiftyThree&lt;/a&gt; again on the &lt;a href='http://fiftythree.com/paper'&gt;Paper website&lt;/a&gt;. Write-up coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned on a 3‑month sabbatical</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/sabbatical</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 09:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/sabbatical</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sabbatical.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sabbatical&quot;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I picked up a heavy stream of client work that I just couldn’t turn down. A couple of the projects were delayed, aligning all of their deadlines to form the perfect storm. After about two months straight of working days, nights, and weekends, I wrapped up every last one of them. I was exhausted. I needed rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, that overload of client work padded my bank account enough so that I could take some time off. The original plan was to devote a month to getting my life back in order again, both mentally and physically. I would start exercising, reading, and socializing again. I spent too much time heads-down at my computer and not enough time away from it. This was my chance. But instead of one month, I ended up taking off three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Forced time off&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no agenda, I began establishing routines. I joined a gym (and actually went) and set up a weekly email for basketball in Brooklyn, playing every weekend and occasionally throughout the week. I started each morning with a cup of pour over coffee at home and often rolled into the studio around 11. For the first time in a long while, I didn’t feel in a rush to get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week without work, however, I felt fully rested and ready to dive back in. The most surprising and unexpected realization to come out of this sabbatical is that I didn’t need three months—I didn’t even need one. I know now that a single week is all I need to reset after a long sprint. I could’ve returned to work early, but I refrained from doing so. I forced myself to take more time off, as if it were mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Just say no to clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also forced myself to say no to any client gig that came my way, no matter how tempting the opportunity—I simply said I was on sabbatical. Instead of worrying about missing out, I felt empowered. I had a confindence and restraint that I don’t think I’ve ever had since I started freelancing. And aside from feeling like a total badass, I also witnessed a shift in how clients responded to the news. “Taking time off” is one thing, but being “on sabbatical” carries a lot more weight. Now, instead of clients coming to me with a deadline, they wanted to work around my schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week went by and the urge to return grew stronger. I don’t take vacations very often, if at all, because I can’t &lt;em&gt;stay&lt;/em&gt; on vacation. If I’m away from the studio for a week, on day 2, I have enough ideas to leave me itching to get back. This sabbatical was no different. Leading into it, I formed the idea for &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt;, a freelancer tool that would bring peace of mind to those on their own. The main reason behind it is to help avoid those hectic months that encouraged the sabbatical—I should’ve seen the storm coming and planned accordingly, so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to take so much time off. With this new idea brewing, my vacation from work became a vacation from just client work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The need for variety&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was heads-down at my desk again working on this new app. The first few weeks were amazing—working on a personal project full-time feels like I got away with something. After a while, though, I realized that I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; client work to bring variety back to the table, along with challenges other than my own. Knowing exactly what I’ll be working on day after day is one of the reasons I quit my job. The appeal of freelancing is that every day could be completely different from the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This need grew. The more I worked on the app, the more I looked forward to client work. I now see client work as an essential ingredient to my productivity. When I’m obligated to work on a client project, I become really good at utilizing the time I’m not working on it. 7pm no longer means it’s time to call it a day—it now means that I have a good five hours to work on something else. I know this isn’t a healthy way to think, but I also know that I’m happiest when I’m producing good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Planning the return&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a few weeks remaining, I started to plan the months to follow—finally accepting client work again and preparing to ramp up. This time around, however, I wore this new sense of confidence—I felt more prepared than ever before. I realized that when I pause client work, I can clearly see what I need to do differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to rethink how I approach client work. With Cushion as my primary focus, I could afford to take on less. Instead of stacking project upon project, leading to that perfect storm, I could settle with one at a time. This way, I wouldn’t need to take another sabbatical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Cost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, this 3-month sabbatical cost me $23,116.46. Granted it included trips to Portland and Iceland, it was still a huge financial hit to my wallet. As a freelancer, I’ve grown an incredibly thick skin to news like this, so I took a deep breath and just accepted it. I’ve always wanted to take a sabbatical and I finally did it, but now I know I could just escape for a week in a brand new car instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/etsy</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/etsy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/etsy-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;etsy-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style='text-align: center'&gt;I recently worked with &lt;a href='http://etsy.com'&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt; on an internal website. This is &lt;a href='https://www.etsy.com/shop/STORnewyork'&gt;my favorite Etsy seller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/experiments</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/experiments</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uptime.destroytoday.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uptime.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;uptime&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week in Iceland, I returned to Brooklyn on Monday. Knowing I leave for Portland on Sunday, I didn’t want to get back into the thick of things with &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt; just to have any work broken up and left for after the trip. Because of this, I decided to spend this week cleaning up and tackling long overdue to-dos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Experiments” section of my website was highest on my list. It existed in the previous version, but slipped through the cracks in the redesign. I can’t clearly describe this section, but all of the projects within follow a common theme—they don’t bring in money. I made them just because.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project is a rewrite of an old one—&lt;a href=&quot;/experiments/uptime&quot;&gt;Uptime&lt;/a&gt;. Back when I was first learning Ruby, I thought I’d make a dead-simple app that did one thing—track the uptime of my website. That on its own is a bit boring, so I designed it in the style of warehouse injury signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With absolutely no experience with Ruby, I wrote the single-page app on &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt;, which is the equivalent to building a LEGO house with a construction crew. This time around, with a few years of Ruby under my belt, I spent an afternoon and rebuilt it on the lightweight &lt;a href=&quot;http://sinatrarb.com&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; framework. I’m also now hosting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/destroytoday/uptime&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; on Github, in case anyone wants their own uptime page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, I stopped experimenting. Over the next few days, I plan to add a few more of my older “experiments” and continue posting more as I make them. I’m hoping it will bring more variety into my work schedule, allowing me to take the occasional afternoon to focus on a random idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uptime</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/experiments/uptime</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 20:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/experiments/uptime</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uptime.destroytoday.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/uptime.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;uptime&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uptime.destroytoday.com&quot;&gt;Uptime&lt;/a&gt; is a simple Ruby app that tracks the downtime of &lt;a href=&quot;http://destroytoday.com&quot;&gt;destroytoday.com&lt;/a&gt; in the style of warehouse injury signs. I’ve always loved these signs for their attempt to motivate workers while providing a safety record for all to see. Safety becomes a game where the workers try to top their highest “score”, or days without injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/destroytoday/uptime&quot;&gt;View source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Friends interview</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/web-friends-interview</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 10:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/web-friends-interview</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webfriends.io/season/2/episode/2/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/web-friends-interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;web-friends-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet and real-life friend, &lt;a href=&quot;http://garthdb.com&quot;&gt;Garth Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt;, invited me onto his aptly named podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://webfriends.io&quot;&gt;Web Friends&lt;/a&gt;. I shared a handful of pro tips about freelancing and we reminisced about my &lt;a href=&quot;/work/destroytwitter&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; from back in the day. If you’re thinking of quitting your full-time job for the freelance world, but don’t really want to follow through, don’t &lt;a href=&quot;http://webfriends.io/season/2/episode/2/&quot;&gt;listen to this interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the Carousel website with Dropbox</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/building-the-carousel-website</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/building-the-carousel-website</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/carousel-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;carousel-hero&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine and designer at Dropbox, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/colin_dunn&quot;&gt;Colin Dunn&lt;/a&gt;, reached out to me in January. He asked if I would mind him referring me to one of their project managers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/prestontweets&quot;&gt;Preston Hershorn&lt;/a&gt;, for an upcoming gig. Of course, I didn’t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke a few times on the phone, discussing a mystery project that needed a marketing website. I was fresh off of building the &lt;a href=&quot;/work/fiftythree&quot;&gt;Pencil website&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiftythree.com&quot;&gt;FiftyThree&lt;/a&gt;, and interested in building more of these single-page websites with a touch of something special. These websites allowed me to return to my roots of experimenting with code while also serving an actual purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew out to San Francisco to work in-house at Dropbox for a week. On the first day, I sat in on a team meeting to review the state of this mystery project, named “Carousel”. A few team members provided an overview of the branding, along with its history. They demo’d the app itself, their original idea for the website, and storyboards for the upcoming video. It was impressive to see such a large-scale project represented by such a determined team. There was no question they all believed in Carousel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='left video-outer' style='max-width: 300px'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 210%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at Dropbox HQ, I worked on the mobile website, which would step the viewer through several views. A stack of photos would fall, arranging each photo on the device, to fill in the app’s content. Several transitions would play out, demonstrating the app’s main draw—sharing photos. The photos would then return to a stack and prompt the viewer to download the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these steps felt very clear-cut, I decided to treat each one as a “slide”. Instead of using a traditional scroll, and adding yet another moving part to the already active page, I locked it in place. I then listened for touch events and advanced to the next step with any vertical movement longer than a thumb’s radius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://byalicelee.com&quot;&gt;Alice Lee&lt;/a&gt;, provided me with flats and we discussed possible transitions. I first used Chrome’s device emulator to test the website, but then moved to using an actual device. This helped in discovering a few key areas of improvement where we could tie the transitions closer to the gestures of the viewer. Since we were swiping up to advance, I wanted the content to feel like it was being pushed with the viewer’s thumb or finger—the logo would scale down in the direction of the swipe and the stack of photos would be pulled up from the bottom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, the stack of photos on the last slide returned to the bottom of the stage, but this felt unnatural, as if the photos were swimming against the current of the swipe. I reversed the positioning of the stack, placing them at the top of the stage, with the content below. Again, following the direction of the swipe, this adjustment really pulled the ending together. The last slide now appears to be the continuation of first slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='video-outer'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 77%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrapped up the mobile website that week, with exception for a few content tweaks throughout the rest of the project. After returning home to Brooklyn, I started on the desktop version. Dropbox wanted a completely different experience from mobile, but they also made it clear they didn’t want a separate “m.carousel.com” subdomain. Considering the mobile version used CSS for all of the transitions, I knew I would need to start from scratch with the desktop’s stylesheet. I ended up using the same HTML as the mobile version, but swapping out the stylesheets based on media queries on the stylesheet tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original design of the desktop website used scroll-based breakpoints to trigger each transition. The text would follow one-to-one with the scroll and the device would remain fixed. This worked, but with the constant movement of the text, the viewer would be forced to switch focus between the two sides of the page. I switched the text to a fixed position and animated it in parallel with the device. This felt better, but there was a lot of waiting between transitions—and the wait would grow longer with the height of the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With only a couple weeks left, we decided to scrap the triggered animations and start over. Instead of relying on harsh breakpoints, we would track the animation with the scroll. To soften the feel, I took a page out of my Flash days and added friction to the scroll. This allowed the animations to ease into place without feeling so jarring. A few people at Dropbox looked at the website and felt the animations needed to snap into place better. At that time, they were a bit loose—you could easily scrub through the entire animation with a couple swipes on the trackpad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='video-outer'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 77%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely didn’t want to return to the triggered approach from before, so I improvised. Since I was already using friction for a softer feel, I could simply increase the friction based on the scroll’s proximity to each lockpoint. In the code, I call these “speed bumps” and that’s exactly what they are. And, to make these speed bumps less apparent, I ease the friction based on the actual distance. This was enough to achieve the slick movement of the transitions while snapping each slide into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final week, there were several more revisions to the content. Initially, the desktop version had twice as many transitions, with each one split into separate parts. The second slide would swipe the screen up to portray a greater collection of photos. The third slide would transition into the conversation view with a fourth slide for easing the second message in from the bottom. We simplified these transitions by combining them, one by one, until we were left with three essential slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch, I let out a great sigh of relief. This project took a lot out of me because it consisted of countless technical challenges and several changes in direction late in the game. I’m happy with the end result, though. If we settled at any point instead of pushing through the difficult decisions, I think we would have been left with regret. Looking back, I’m incredibly grateful and fortunate that such a small gesture on Colin’s part, of putting my name in the hat, led to this collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://carousel.com&quot;&gt;carousel.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On sabbatical</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/on-sabbatical</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/on-sabbatical</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I start my sabbatical. This is a first for me and, perhaps, an over-the-top reaction to the fact that I don’t take any time off, but I need it. With a first quarter consisting of nothing but client work, I know I need to slow down and give myself some time to reset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year started out promising, with a few potential gigs, but before long, each one fell through. I found myself going into February with only negative line items on my bank statement and not a single confirmed project. It was tough to endure, but something told me to wait it out—that these project didn’t pan out for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, all of a sudden, I reunited with a previous client, &lt;a href=&quot;http://chr.ma&quot;&gt;Chroma&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/colin_dunn&quot;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; at Dropbox put in a good word for me. I had two confirmed projects and more than enough work to keep me busy until April. On top of that, Mailbox asked if I could take on their website as well. At this point, I &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; had more than enough work to keep me busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a little under two months, I finished &lt;a href=&quot;http://chr.ma&quot;&gt;all&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://carousel.com&quot;&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailboxapp.com&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; as well as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ableparris.com&quot;&gt;personal website&lt;/a&gt; for my friend. This resulted in an incredible number of late nights and long weekends, but also, enough income to provide a comfortable runway into summer. I considered taking on more client work, but then I stopped and realized—I should take this time and invest it in myself. What else could I do in two months?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I shift focus to &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Cushion&lt;/a&gt;, but I also start from scratch with my day-to-day routine. These past two months have proven that just because I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; work on four websites simultaneousely doesn’t mean I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;. By the end of this sabbatical, I want to be excited to take on new work, but mindful in deciding how much is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Start interview</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/the-start-interview</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/the-start-interview</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thestart.fm/interviews/the-flyer-guy&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/the-start-interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;the-start-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder='0' height='36px' scrolling='no' seamless src='https://simplecast.fm/e/1949?style=dark' width='100%'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/nr&quot;&gt;Nick Rovisa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/patrickbjohnson&quot;&gt;Patrick Johnson&lt;/a&gt; invited me to join them on their podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thestart.fm/interviews/the-flyer-guy&quot;&gt;The Start&lt;/a&gt;. We covered my entrance into design at RISD pre-college, my first internship-turned-job at a small studio in Baltimore, and the origin of the name “Destroy Today”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cushion</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/cushion</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 16:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/cushion</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/timeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I registered a new domain name and published a new website—&lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;cushionapp.com&lt;/a&gt;. For the past few months, I’ve been nurturing an idea. This idea started as a simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://dstry.it/TVi6&quot;&gt;prototype&lt;/a&gt; for seeing how long a freelancer could coast, based on their income applied to their monthly expenses. I shared this idea with the late night Twitter crowd and discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/destroytoday/status/425496976294412288&quot;&gt;they liked it&lt;/a&gt;, too. I could feel I was onto something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the following weeks, I shaped the idea. I started thinking about my day-to-day as a freelancer and wondered what would make it easier. Considering the original idea, I thought about breaking income into three types—deposited, pending, and potential—then, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dstry.it/UGwQ&quot;&gt;mapping&lt;/a&gt; them over time. I thought about my existing projects and how I wished I could &lt;a href=&quot;http://dstry.it/UQxb&quot;&gt;track&lt;/a&gt; when they were delayed or dragged on too long. I thought about potential projects and what it would be like if I could visually &lt;a href=&quot;http://dstry.it/UUN2&quot;&gt;weigh&lt;/a&gt; the pros and cons. After designing several of these prototypes, I realized just how much I needed this app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to commit was easy, but I also made another decision—to go on this trip alone. When I first started building apps, like &lt;a href=&quot;/work/destroyflickr&quot;&gt;DestroyFlickr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/work/destroytwitter&quot;&gt;DestroyTwitter&lt;/a&gt;, I worked by myself, so I had free reign to take them wherever I wanted to go. Instead of focusing on the same features that every other app already had, I would experiment. I would implement the kind of features that none of the bigger apps would ever bother adding. And, sometimes, those unique features would be what set my apps apart from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Cushion, I also want to focus on its feel and make it as personal an experience as possible. Rather than aim for unbelievable growth, I’d like to establish Cushion as a independent app, where users can have a direct connection to the person behind it. By creating an account, you are also creating a relationship. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in following along, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hold a Pencil podcast interview</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/how-to-hold-a-pencil-podcast-interview</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 10:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/how-to-hold-a-pencil-podcast-interview</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/reubeningber&quot;&gt;Reuben Inger&lt;/a&gt; invited me to join him on his podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://howtoholdapencil.com/episode/017/&quot;&gt;How to Hold a Pencil&lt;/a&gt;, for an interview about how I started in the design/dev world. I also talked about taking the leap into freelancing and the fears and freedoms that come with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder='0' height='36px' scrolling='no' seamless src='https://simplecast.fm/e/1926?style=dark' width='100%'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question marks in Liquid variable names</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/findings/question-marks-in-liquid-variable-names</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 17:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/findings/question-marks-in-liquid-variable-names</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; is a very forgiving templating language, which is part of why I love it. I sometimes find myself pushing Liquid to its limits to see how much it will allow before throwing an error. With a history of Ruby under my belt, I’ve become accustomed to using boolean methods that end with a question mark (ex: &lt;code&gt;new?&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;blank?&lt;/code&gt;, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt rather adventureous one day, so I tried following this same approach with Liquid. I created a metadata value named &lt;code&gt;inverted?&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://siteleaf.com&quot;&gt;Siteleaf&lt;/a&gt; to indicate that the page should use white text instead of black. In my template, I added the conditional &lt;code&gt;{% if meta.inverted? %}&lt;/code&gt; to insert a CSS class into body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I discovered that Liquid has no objections with hyphens in variable names, either. Instead of &lt;code&gt;background_color&lt;/code&gt;, I can use the CSS syntax &lt;code&gt;background-color&lt;/code&gt; and access it with &lt;code&gt;{{ meta.background-color }}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid, I love you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailbox</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/mailbox</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 22:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/mailbox</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mailbox-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;mailbox-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in-house at Dropbox, working on the &lt;a href=&quot;/work/carousel&quot;&gt;Carousel website&lt;/a&gt;, the PM for Mailbox, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/lizarmistead&quot;&gt;Liz Armistead&lt;/a&gt;, caught a glimpse of my work on the mobile website. She leaned in my direction and asked about my availability—would I have extra time to also take on the Mailbox website? Over the years, I’ve realized that I work best under pressure, but two major projects with the same deadline is floor-of-the-ocean pressure. Continuing a pattern of complete disregard for personal health, I said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='video-outer'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 77%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/mailbox.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/mailbox.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/mailbox.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/mailbox.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the website took a number of turns before I was given the green light. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/morganknutson&quot;&gt;Morgan Knutson&lt;/a&gt; led the final version, landing on using videos to demo the many gestures within the app. Upon scrolling the website, the videos will autoplay once they come into view. When a video falls out of view, it pauses. It’s a straight-forward approach, but very effective, showcasing exactly how the app works without hitting you over the head with effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mailbox-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mailbox-devices&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The responsive side of the Mailbox website is all about replacing content. Reflowing down to the tablet breakpoint, the website first swaps out all videos for stills. As it narrows to the phone breakpoint, icons replace the stills and the top image is replaced with the Mailbox logo. The most complex part of the responsive implementation would definitely be the line of devices at the bottom of the website—the phones fit perfectly together, but at smaller scales, the laptop is too much. Because of this, I move the laptop below its copy when it hits the phone breakpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the Mailbox website wasn’t as ambitious as the Carousel website, I feel its strength lies in its restraint to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; go over the top. Because the app’s ease and simplicity is its main appeal, the goal of the website is to showcase Mailbox’s key gestures and get users right into the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mailboxapp.com&quot;&gt;Visit the Mailbox website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carousel</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/carousel</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 22:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/carousel</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/carousel-logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;dropbox-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine and designer at Dropbox, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/colin_dunn&quot;&gt;Colin Dunn&lt;/a&gt;, reached out to me in January. He asked if I would mind him referring me to one of their project managers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/prestontweets&quot;&gt;Preston Hershorn&lt;/a&gt;, for an upcoming gig. Of course, I didn’t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke a few times on the phone, discussing a mystery project that needed a marketing website. I was fresh off of building the &lt;a href=&quot;/work/fiftythree&quot;&gt;Pencil website&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiftythree.com&quot;&gt;FiftyThree&lt;/a&gt;, and interested in building more of these single-page websites with a touch of something special. These websites allowed me to return to my roots of experimenting with code while also serving an actual purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew out to San Francisco to work in-house at Dropbox for a week. On the first day, I sat in on a team meeting to review the state of this mystery project, named “Carousel”. A few team members provided an overview of the branding, along with its history. They demo’d the app itself, their original idea for the website, and storyboards for the upcoming video. It was impressive to see such a large-scale project represented by such a determined team. There was no question they all believed in Carousel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='left video-outer' style='max-width: 300px'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 210%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-mobile.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at Dropbox HQ, I worked on the mobile website, which would step the viewer through several views. A stack of photos would fall, arranging each photo on the device, to fill in the app’s content. Several transitions would play out, demonstrating the app’s main draw—sharing photos. The photos would then return to a stack and prompt the viewer to download the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these steps felt very clear-cut, I decided to treat each one as a “slide”. Instead of using a traditional scroll, and adding yet another moving part to the already active page, I locked it in place. I then listened for touch events and advanced to the next step with any vertical movement longer than a thumb’s radius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://byalicelee.com&quot;&gt;Alice Lee&lt;/a&gt;, provided me with flats and we discussed possible transitions. I first used Chrome’s device emulator to test the website, but then moved to using an actual device. This helped in discovering a few key areas of improvement where we could tie the transitions closer to the gestures of the viewer. Since we were swiping up to advance, I wanted the content to feel like it was being pushed with the viewer’s thumb or finger—the logo would scale down in the direction of the swipe and the stack of photos would be pulled up from the bottom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, the stack of photos on the last slide returned to the bottom of the stage, but this felt unnatural, as if the photos were swimming against the current of the swipe. I reversed the positioning of the stack, placing them at the top of the stage, with the content below. Again, following the direction of the swipe, this adjustment really pulled the ending together. The last slide now appears to be the continuation of first slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='video-outer'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 77%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-intro.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrapped up the mobile website that week, with exception for a few content tweaks throughout the rest of the project. After returning home to Brooklyn, I started on the desktop version. Dropbox wanted a completely different experience from mobile, but they also made it clear they didn’t want a separate “m.carousel.com” subdomain. Considering the mobile version used CSS for all of the transitions, I knew I would need to start from scratch with the desktop’s stylesheet. I ended up using the same HTML as the mobile version, but swapping out the stylesheets based on media queries on the stylesheet tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original design of the desktop website used scroll-based breakpoints to trigger each transition. The text would follow one-to-one with the scroll and the device would remain fixed. This worked, but with the constant movement of the text, the viewer would be forced to switch focus between the two sides of the page. I switched the text to a fixed position and animated it in parallel with the device. This felt better, but there was a lot of waiting between transitions—and the wait would grow longer with the height of the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With only a couple weeks left, we decided to scrap the triggered animations and start over. Instead of relying on harsh breakpoints, we would track the animation with the scroll. To soften the feel, I took a page out of my Flash days and added friction to the scroll. This allowed the animations to ease into place without feeling so jarring. A few people at Dropbox looked at the website and felt the animations needed to snap into place better. At that time, they were a bit loose—you could easily scrub through the entire animation with a couple swipes on the trackpad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='video-outer'&gt;
    &lt;div class='video-inner' style='padding-bottom: 77%'&gt;
        &lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; poster=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.jpg&quot; autoplay=&quot;autoplay&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
            Video tag not supported. Download the video &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/carousel-conversation.mp4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely didn’t want to return to the triggered approach from before, so I improvised. Since I was already using friction for a softer feel, I could simply increase the friction based on the scroll’s proximity to each lockpoint. In the code, I call these “speed bumps” and that’s exactly what they are. And, to make these speed bumps less apparent, I ease the friction based on the actual distance. This was enough to achieve the slick movement of the transitions while snapping each slide into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final week, there were several more revisions to the content. Initially, the desktop version had twice as many transitions, with each one split into separate parts. The second slide would swipe the screen up to portray a greater collection of photos. The third slide would transition into the conversation view with a fourth slide for easing the second message in from the bottom. We simplified these transitions by combining them, one by one, until we were left with three essential slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch, I let out a great sigh of relief. This project took a lot out of me because it consisted of countless technical challenges and several changes in direction late in the game. I’m happy with the end result, though. If we settled at any point instead of pushing through the difficult decisions, I think we would have been left with regret. Looking back, I’m incredibly grateful and fortunate that such a small gesture on Colin’s part, of putting my name in the hat, led to this collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://carousel.com&quot;&gt;Visit the Carousel website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix widows with non‑breaking spaces</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/findings/fix-widows-with-non-breaking-spaces</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/findings/fix-widows-with-non-breaking-spaces</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After learning the ins and outs of typography in design school, I started seeing the world through new eyes. Unfortunately, these eyes focus on the imperfections, like a single word on its own line, known as a “widow”. These imperfections are everywhere on the web because type isn’t laid out as carefully as it is in print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While CSS &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a &lt;code&gt;widows&lt;/code&gt; property, it’s for handling widow lines in column layouts—not words. Because of this, we need to rely on a hack—placing a non-breaking space between the last two words. In the past, I used the &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/code&gt; entity, but stopped because of how much it clutters the code. Now, I use an actual non-breaking space character, which can be created with &lt;code&gt;option+space&lt;/code&gt;. This works as long as you have &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;#39;UTF-8&amp;#39;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this approach because it’s clean and easy. The non-breaking space looks like any other space and when used in titles, it even prevents widows in the UI of &lt;a href=&quot;http://siteleaf.com&quot;&gt;Siteleaf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m well-aware of the more automated ways of handling widows, like using the &lt;code&gt;String.replace&lt;/code&gt; method in Javascript with a regular expression, but I try to refrain from using JS when there are HTML or CSS‑based alternatives. Also, manually inserting a non-breaking space allows me to pick and choose where to prevent widows, in cases where a title widow is long enough to live on its own line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CreativeMornings</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/blog/creativemornings</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/blog/creativemornings</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;http://creativemornings.com/talks/embed/want-to-speak-at-creativemornings/1&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;height: 0; padding-top: 56.2%&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past December, I spoke at &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativemornings.com&quot;&gt;CreativeMornings&lt;/a&gt;, a breakfast lecture series for the creative community with 65 chapters worldwide and growing. The New York venue is located several blocks from my co-working space, &lt;a href=&quot;http://studiomates.com&quot;&gt;Studiomates&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m often in attendance. This time, however, I was fortunate enough to take the stage. Considering the month’s theme, “Make,” my talk focused on my dad and how he made me into the “maker” I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For an extended transcription of my talk, you can refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/my-dad&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chroma</title>
      <link>http://destroytoday.com/work/chroma</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Jonnie Hallman</author>
      <guid>http://destroytoday.com/work/chroma</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/chroma-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;chroma-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style='text-align: center'&gt;Visit the &lt;a href='http://chr.ma'&gt;Chrome website&lt;/a&gt;. Write-up coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
